<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Big Data in Biomedicine on Big Data in Biomedicine</title>
    <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Big Data in Biomedicine on Big Data in Biomedicine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Data als Wegbereiter der Präzisionsmedizin</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/talk/igld/igld/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/talk/igld/igld/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open positions for PhD students and Postdocs within the Collaborative Research Centre (CRC) 1371 in bioinformatics, medical informatics or computational biology (m/f/d) starting 01.02.2019</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/post/job-ad-inf01-crc1371/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/post/job-ad-inf01-crc1371/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We are looking for skilled PhD students and Postdocs to contribute in building a central IT platform for gut microbiome research. On the medical informatics side, we seek expertise to build up a medical data integration platform that enables harmonization and analysis of sensitive data while adhering to data protection requirements. On the bioinformatics side, we seek expertise to build and integrate pipelines for systematic analysis of heterogeneous experimental data ranging from 16S ribosomal RNA to complex metabolome profiles. Moreover, we seek expertise for developing and integrating state-of-the-art statistical and network analysis methods into the platform. These methods will facilitate knowledge extraction, biomarker discovery and hypothesis generation for the CRC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project description&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gut microbiome plays a fundamental role in health and disease. CRC 1371 (Speaker Prof. Dr. Dirk Haller) focuses on the digestive tract and proposes an interdisciplinary approach to characterizing the functional relevance of microbiome signatures in the context of inflammation and cancer. Within the INF01 subproject of CRC 1371, we assemble an interdisciplinary team with expertise in medical informatics and bioinformatics to build a central IT platform for the collection and processing of human and non-human clinical, para-clinical and experimental data produced in CRC 1371. In building this platform, you will join a huge collaborative effort to assemble the most comprehensive knowledgebase of the gut microbiome and you will have a chance to bring in your own ideas to unravel the role of the microbiome in health and disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Candidates hold a Master degree (or equivalent) or PhD in computer science, medical informatics, bioinformatics, computational biology or biotechnology. They are open minded, active and have a good command of the English language (oral and written). The collaborative character of this project requires excellent team and communication skills as well as technical skills in software engineering and data analysis. Knowledge of Java and / or R is of advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;contact-persons&#34;&gt;Contact persons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fabian Prasser &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:fabian.prasser@tum.de&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;fabian.prasser@tum.de&lt;/a&gt;
Institute of Medical Informatics, Statistics and Epidemiology, TUM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ilias Lagkouvardos &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:ilias.lagkouvardos@tum.de&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ilias.lagkouvardos@tum.de&lt;/a&gt;
ZIEL Institute for Food and Health, TUM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jan Baumbach &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jan.baumbach@wzw.tum.de&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;jan.baumbach@wzw.tum.de&lt;/a&gt;
Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics, TUM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markus List &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:markus.list@wzw.tum.de&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;markus.list@wzw.tum.de&lt;/a&gt;
Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics, TUM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;application&#34;&gt;Application&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicants are asked to send one pdf file to the contact person. The file includes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cover letter,
curriculum vitae,
copies of academic degrees and transcripts of records,85354
preferences of projects (optional),
contact information for at least one letter of recommendation,
list of publications with link for downloading (Do not include your publications in the pdf file).
As an equal opportunity and affirmative action employer, TUM explicitly encourages applications from women as well as from all others who would bring additional diversity dimensions to the university’s research and teaching strategies. Preference will be given to disabled candidates with essentially the same qualifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-protection-information&#34;&gt;Data Protection Information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you apply for a position with the Technical University of Munich (TUM), you are submitting personal information. With regard to personal information, please take note of the Datenschutzhinweise gemäß Art. 13 Datenschutz-Grundverordnung (DSGVO) zur Erhebung und Verarbeitung von personenbezogenen Daten im Rahmen Ihrer Bewerbung. (data protection information on collecting and processing personal data contained in your application in accordance with Art. 13 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)). By submitting your application, you confirm that you have acknowledged the above data protection information of TUM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming challenges in the integrative analysis of epigenomic data</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/talk/icb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/talk/icb/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFP suppresses breast cancer cell growth by TES-mediated upregulation of the transcription factor DDIT3</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/publication/block-2019-cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/publication/block-2019-cfp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome-wide endogenous RNA networks highlight novel biomarkers in cancer</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/talk/imm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/talk/imm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostDoc Position in Network Epigenomics</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/post/job-announcement-nov18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/post/job-announcement-nov18/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Full time position for a PostDoc to fill in the newly established group for Big Data in Biomedicine at the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics, Technical University of Munich, Freising, Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-description&#34;&gt;Project description&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A major research barrier in systems biomedicine is that most of the currently used gene-gene interaction networks are not cell type-specific and neglect much of our current understanding of cellular regulation (i.e. enhancers and repressors). The EpiMap project of the International Human Epigenome Consortium currently integrates and harmonizes multi-omics data from 1000 epigenomes, offering a unique chance to overcome this barrier. The aim of this research project is to use state-of-the-art machine learning techniques for multitask and transfer learning to construct robust cell-type-specific molecular interaction networks. Such networks will allow researchers to put their experimental results in a cell type-specific context and thus pave the way towards adding an epigenetic perspective to biomedical research in general and to systems medicine in particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-qualifications&#34;&gt;Your qualifications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recent PhD in Computational Biology, Bioinformatics, Genomics, Epigenetics or a related field.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong experience with handling RNA-seq, small RNA-seq, WGBS, RRBS, ChiP-seq data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong experience with systems biology and network analysis techniques&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong experience with advanced machine learning techniques, e.g. SVNs, RF, CNN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong experience in R, Python or Java&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good experience in using compute clusters / HPC environments and Docker / Singularity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solid understanding of molecular biology in general and epigenetic mechanisms in particular&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to independently carry out a challenging research project in an international collaboration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fluency in English in written and spoken language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-we-offer&#34;&gt;What we offer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics you will find a supportive and productive research environment with a young, dynamic team of more than 20 international researchers at different stages in their career and education. Find us online at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.exbio.de&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.exbio.de&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://biomedical-big-data.de&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://biomedical-big-data.de&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The position is available starting immediately and initially limited for 3 year with a gross salary calculated according to A13 TV-L.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested? Send your application including your CV, the most relevant publications and two reference letters to markus.list@wzw.tum.de.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-protection-information&#34;&gt;Data Protection Information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you apply for a position with the Technical University of Munich (TUM), you are submitting personal information. With regard to personal information, please take note of the Datenschutzhinweise gemäß Art. 13 Datenschutz-Grundverordnung (DSGVO) zur Erhebung und Verarbeitung von personenbezogenen Daten im Rahmen Ihrer Bewerbung. (data protection information on collecting and processing personal data contained in your application in accordance with Art. 13 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)). By submitting your application, you confirm that you have acknowledged the above data protection information of TUM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive evaluation of cell-type quantification methods for immuno-oncology</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/publication/sturm-2018-bx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/publication/sturm-2018-bx/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing large-scale epigenomic data with DeepBlue</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/talk/bioc2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/talk/bioc2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Competing endogenous RNA network inference</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/project/sponge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 19:39:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/project/sponge/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>De novo network enrichment</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/project/kpm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 19:39:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/project/kpm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FeatureCloud</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/project/featurecloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 19:39:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/project/featurecloud/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Throughput Screening</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/project/hts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 19:39:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/project/hts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large-scale epigenomics data analysis</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/project/deepblue/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 19:39:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/project/deepblue/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REPO-TRIAL</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/project/repo-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 19:39:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/project/repo-trial/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome-wide endogenous RNA networks highlight novel biomarkers in cancer</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/talk/cemm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/talk/cemm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
