<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Big Data in Biomedicine</title>
    <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Big Data in Biomedicine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://biomedical-big-data.de/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Open positions for PhD students and Postdocs within the Collaborative Research Centre (CRC) 1371 in bioinformatics, medical informatics or computational biology (m/f/d) starting 01.02.2019</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/post/job-ad-inf01-crc1371/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/post/job-ad-inf01-crc1371/</guid>
      <description>We are looking for skilled PhD students and Postdocs to contribute in building a central IT platform for gut microbiome research. On the medical informatics side, we seek expertise to build up a medical data integration platform that enables harmonization and analysis of sensitive data while adhering to data protection requirements. On the bioinformatics side, we seek expertise to build and integrate pipelines for systematic analysis of heterogeneous experimental data ranging from 16S ribosomal RNA to complex metabolome profiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PostDoc Position in Network Epigenomics</title>
      <link>https://biomedical-big-data.de/post/job-announcement-nov18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://biomedical-big-data.de/post/job-announcement-nov18/</guid>
      <description>Full time position for a PostDoc to fill in the newly established group for Big Data in Biomedicine at the Chair of Experimental Bioinformatics, Technical University of Munich, Freising, Germany.
Project description A major research barrier in systems biomedicine is that most of the currently used gene-gene interaction networks are not cell type-specific and neglect much of our current understanding of cellular regulation (i.e. enhancers and repressors). The EpiMap project of the International Human Epigenome Consortium currently integrates and harmonizes multi-omics data from 1000 epigenomes, offering a unique chance to overcome this barrier.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>